{
    "id": "88e312e09887433592be1919516ded80",
    "title": "Modal Auxiliary Verbs Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She may …………………….. his name.",
            "description": "After modal auxiliary verbs, we use the infinitive without to. There is no –s in the third person singular.",
            "answers": [
                "know",
                "knows",
                "knowing"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "3346aa03bbb04dd9a4620b326e8443c1"
        },
        {
            "question": "She ……………………….. speak English.",
            "description": "Modal verbs have no –s in the third person singular.",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "cans"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "534a6cb948a54257b129eab7caa2f3e3"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………….. do that.",
            "description": "Modal auxiliary verbs make questions and negatives without do.",
            "answers": [
                "not should",
                "does not should",
                "should not"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "1f7ce1711dac416886aee7adc4bf0faf"
        },
        {
            "question": "You must …………………………. now.",
            "description": "After modals, we use the infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "to leave",
                "leave",
                "leaving"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "bc0cb889721746948951da000e9a5b43"
        },
        {
            "question": "The walls ought to ………………………… one of these days.",
            "description": "Passive infinitives can be used after modals.",
            "answers": [
                "paint",
                "be painted",
                "be painting"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "2d5b8a8021174e1eac73977e9cfd34a0"
        },
        {
            "question": "I really ……………………… to work hard in those days.",
            "description": "The modal verb must does not have a past tense form. We use other verbs when necessary.",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "had",
                "must",
                "musted"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ed8b675acdd942789fa4212f63b426c3"
        },
        {
            "question": "You ………………………….. me you were coming.",
            "description": "We can use have + past participle after a modal verb to express a past idea.",
            "answers": [
                "should tell",
                "should told",
                "should have told"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "146293b8e6d44d84829c682671843014"
        },
        {
            "question": "‘Suma hasn’t arrived yet.’ ‘She ……………………….. the train.’",
            "description": "We can use have + past participle after a modal verb to express a past idea.\r\nNote that can is not used to talk about logical possibility. ",
            "answers": [
                "might miss",
                "might have missed",
                "can have missed"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d18ac7f464e9453a8672d71eccd7ae01"
        },
        {
            "question": "She …………………………. be in London or Paris.",
            "description": "We do not use can in affirmative clauses to indicate logical possibility.",
            "answers": [
                "could",
                "can"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "0121d91f22b3409786f3296902c1f728"
        },
        {
            "question": "Chennai …………………………. be very hot in March.",
            "description": "We use can to talk about theoretical or habitual possibility.",
            "answers": [
                "may",
                "can",
                "must"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "21548aef7c04456681b6bbda7c0fa7b4"
        },
        {
            "question": "‘Where is Janaki?’ ‘She ………………………… have gone swimming.’",
            "description": "May and might are possible here. We do not use can in affirmative clauses to talk about logical possibility.",
            "answers": [
                "may",
                "might",
                "can"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "688c80e1dc884833919a00672da05eb6"
        },
        {
            "question": "Students ………………………….. use the staff car park.",
            "description": "All of these expressions can be used to talk about prohibition.",
            "answers": [
                "must not",
                "may not",
                "cannot",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "003319448f884642b6b02aa74bc78495"
        }
    ]
}